Finding Aid for the Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0878
42.62 linear feet
Biographical Note
Oliver Cromwell Carmichael was born October 3, 1891 on a farm near Goodwater, Alabama the eighth child and fifth son of the eleven children of Daniel Monroe, a farmer and school teacher and Amanda Lessley Carmichael, also a school teacher and homemaker.
Known as one of the outstanding University administrators and experts on educational philosophy in the country, Oliver Carmichael was the third chancellor of Vanderbilt University during the years 1937–1946.
While at Vanderbilt, Chancellor Carmichael was instrumental in creating in 1937 the Joint University Libraries serving Vanderbilt, Peabody, and Scarritt Colleges. Later, in 1940 he led the efforts to establish the Vanderbilt University Press in order “to emphasize Vanderbilt’s commitment to scholarly research and publication.” Both of these he considered as his most important accomplishments while at Vanderbilt. He also led the university through the years of World War II.
In March of 1967, shortly after his death in September 1966 Carmichael Towers, residence halls at Vanderbilt, were dedicated in his memory. Carmichael Hall at the University of Alabama and the Carmichael Library at Montevallo are also named in his honor.
Collections of his papers are held by Vanderbilt University, the University of Alabama and by the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching in New York.
Education:
Alabama Presbyterian College, Anniston, Alabama for two years
University of Alabama, B.A. 1911; M.A. 1914
Rhodes Scholar from Alabama 1913-1917 at Wadham College, Oxford University taking a B.Sc. diploma in Anthropology.
He was awarded honorary degrees from 21 colleges and universities in the United States over the course of his professional career. They are listed below.
Career:
U.S. Army, World War I
Herbert Hoover’s Commission for Belgian Relief
YMCA work in India and East Africa
Birmingham, Alabama City Schools High School teacher, 1919-1920
High School Principal, 1920–1922
Dean and assistant to the President at Alabama College at Montevallo, 1922-1926
President of Alabama College (a woman’s college), 1926-1935
He was the third Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, serving from 1937–46. Previously he served as Dean and then Vice Chancellor of the University from 1935 until he became Chancellor in 1937.
President of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching 1946–1953
Executive Associate and Member of the Board of Trustees of Carnegie Corporation of New York
President of the University of Alabama 1953-1956
Educational Consultant for the Ford Foundation and Fund for Advancement of Education, 1957 – until his death in September of 1966.
Personal Life:
While a Rhodes Scholar at Wadham College, Oxford, he and a fellow student Harvie Branscomb worked for Herbert Hoover’s Commission for Relief in Belgium and smuggled a politically sensitive letter from Cardinal Mercier through the German lines. Carmichael’s friendship with Harvie Branscomb who succeeded him as the 4th Chancellor of Vanderbilt University shaped Vanderbilt’s destiny for nearly three decades.
He married Ruth Mae Crabtree on July 13, 1918, and they had two sons Oliver C. Carmichael, Jr. born in 1920 and Fred H. Carmichael born in 1922.
Golf and Bridge are the sports he enjoyed most, and reading historical and philosophical essays and novels was his favorite pastime.
He died in Asheville, North Carolina on September 25, 1966 at the age of 74.
Biographical Chronology
1891 Born on October 3 in Goodwater, Alabama
1910 Teacher, one room country school, summer 1910
1911-1914 Received A.B. and M.A. degrees, University of Alabama
1911-1912 Instructor of French and German, secretary of the faculty, Univ. of Ala.
1912-1913 Acting professor of foreign languages, Florence Normal School
1917 Received B. Sc. Degree, Oxford University, England as a Rhodes Scholar at Wadham College
1918 Married Ruth Mae Crabtree on July 13
1919 High school teacher of European history, March–June
1919-1920 Instructor of French, high school
1920-1921 Principal, Henly Elementary School
1921-1922 Principal, Woodlawn High School
1922-1926 Dean and Assistant to President, Alabama College
1926-1935 President, Alabama College
1935-1937 Dean, Graduate School and Senior College, Vanderbilt University
1936-1937 Vice–Chancellor, Vanderbilt University
1937-1946 Chancellor, Vanderbilt University
1946-1953 President, Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
1946-1953 Executive Associate and member of the Board of Trustees of the Carnegie Corporation of New York
1948-1953 Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the New York State University System
1953-1956 President, University of Alabama
1957-1966 Educational Consultant, Ford Foundation, and Fund for Advancement of Education
1966 Died September 25 in Asheville, North Carolina
Scope and Content Note
The papers are comprised of correspondence, his writings including addresses, articles, book manuscripts and institutional reports, and other materials relating to Oliver Carmichael’s long and distinguished career in teaching, university administration, and educational consulting. There are also papers relating to his leadership and service roles at many organizations including Vanderbilt University,
One part of the collection having to do with his presidency at the University of Alabama and the case of Autherine Lucy,a black woman from Shiloh, Alabama who was enrolled, and then suspended, and then expelled from the university, contains photocopies of correspondence relating to this event during the early months of 1956.
These letters reflect a range of opinions on everything from segregation to the students’ violent behavior to Carmichael’s handling of the situation.
The originals of these letters are at the University of Alabama and more information about the case can be found at this website:
http://apps.lib.ua.edu/blogs/coolathoole/2016/02/09/chronicling-uas-first-steps-toward-desegregation/
Also of especial interest in this collection of papers are items relating to his time as Chancellor of Vanderbilt University including a guest book, letters of congratulations, and programs and memorabilia from his installation as Chancellor in early February of 1938.
- The Series
  - Correspondence–Outgoing
    - February 9-11, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - February 12-19, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - March 15–April 5, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - April 6–19, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - April 20, 1034–August 19, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - June 11-12, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - June 14-15, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - June 16-17,1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - June 21–August 10, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - October 25, 1939–December 23, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - September 14, 1946–August 13, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - January 3, 1950–December 23, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January 5–May 6, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - May 7, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - May 8-11, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - May 12-13, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - May 14, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - May 15-19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - May 20-22, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - May 27–June 5, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - June 8-9, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - June 10-16, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - June 17-30, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - July 1-22, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - July 22–30, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - August 3–September 10, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - September 25–December 16, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - January 4–April 6, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - April 8–June 26, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - June 26–September 28, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - October 1–December 20, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - January 3–March 15, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - March 16–May 31, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - June 4–July 30, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - August 1–September 13, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - September 16–October 18, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - October 19–December 29, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - January 3–March 23, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - March 26–July 25, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - July 26–September 29. 1056 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - October 1–November 8, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - November 9-12, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - November 3–15, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - November 16–December 26, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - January 26–June 24, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - June 25–27, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - July 1-10, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - July 15–August 12, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - August 15–29, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - September 2–10, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - September 11–October 16, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - October 17–28, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - October 31–November 16, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - November 20–December 4, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - December 9–31, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - January 4–30, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - February 1–6, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - February 14–March 3, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - March 5–28, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - April 2–28, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - May 6-27, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - June 3–24, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - June 25–July 22, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - August 1–September 17, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - September 24–October 6, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - October 7–15, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - October 17–23, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - October 24–November 8, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - November 10-24, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - November 27-December 31, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - January 4–19, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - January 21–February 2, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - February 4–28, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - March 2–16, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - March 20–30, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - April 1–7, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - April 10–15, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - April 22–May 4, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - May 6–20, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - May 25–June 3, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - June 5, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - June 8–19, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - June 22-24, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - June 25–July 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - July 3–8, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - July 13–15, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - July 20–27, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - July 29–August 10, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - August 14–September 4, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - September 12-23, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - September 24–October 2, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - October 3-12, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - October 14-19, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - October 21–November 5, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - November 7-16, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - November 16, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - November 27–30, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - December 2–14, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - December 15–28, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - January 4–13, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - January 13–25, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - January 27–February 3, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - February 8–17, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - February 22–March 4, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - March 11-18, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - March 25-28, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - April 1–11, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - April 13-25, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - April 27–May 13, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - May 16–June 14, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - June 15-29, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - July 5–August 31, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - September 2–12, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - September 19–21, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - September 23–November 16, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - November 21–December 9, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - December 12, 1960–January 2, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - January 4–23, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - January 25–February 24, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - March 1–31, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - April 3–May 4, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - May 11-24, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - May 27–June 15, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - June 16–July 31, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - August 2–9, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - August 14–29, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - September 4–23, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - October 2–9, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - October 10–November 2, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - November 4–December 4, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - December 11–21, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - January 2-8. 1962 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - January 11–29, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - February 1-27, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - March 1–19, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - March 22–April 6, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - April 10-24, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - April 24–May 8, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - May 11–28, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - June 4–25, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - June 28–July 26, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - July 30–August 2, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - August 3–September 3, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - September 6–20, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - September 24–October 8, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - October 10–17, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - October 22, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - October 24–31, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - November 2-12, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - November 14–30, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - December 3–14, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - December 18-31, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - January 2–21, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - January 23–30, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - February 1–27, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - March 1–22, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - March 20–April 8, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - April 11–29, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - May 1–20, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - May 22–June 7, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - January 10–24, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - June 26–July 12, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - July 15–August 26, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - August 28–September 19, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - September 23–28, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - September 30–October 7, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - October 9–18, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - October 21–30, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - November 1–26, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - November 27–December 30, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - January 3–16, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - January 2–February 5, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - February 10-27, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - March 2–13, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - March 16–April 15, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - April 17–May 6, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - May 11–29, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - June 1–19, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - June 22–July 14, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - July 15-31, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - August 5–31, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - September 4–30, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - October 2–28, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - November 1-27, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - November 30–December 30, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - January 6-29, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - February 2-15, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - February 17–March 17, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - March 22–April 5, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - April 7–19, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - April 21–May 7, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - May 10–28, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - June 2–11, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - June 14–July 7, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - July 9-30, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - August 2–25, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - August 27–September 29, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - October 1–29, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - November 1–29, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - December 2, 1965–January 6, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - n. d.; 1950’s–1960’s; first names only (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence-Incoming
    - Aaron, Thomas R.–Adams, Arthur S. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Arthur S. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Arthur S. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Arthur S. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Adams, Arthurs S.–Adams, William (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Addickes, Ann C.–Alston, J. F. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Alter, Chester M.–Anderson, O. E. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Robert C. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Anderson, Robert C. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Anderson, Roy–Archibald, Elizabeth (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Archie, William C. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Archie, William C. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Archie, William C. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Archie, William C. – Arnold, Carolyn B. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ashby, Eric – Austin, Mary E. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Auten, Joseph L. – Axt, Richard G. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Aycock, W.B. – Ayres, W. L. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Babbidge, Homer D. – Baker, T. P. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Baldwin, Mary A. – Barton, Bruce (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Bashinsky, E.B. – Bayes, William R. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Bealle, J. Rufus – Bell, E.W. (Mrs.) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Belser, Irvine F. – Benitez, Jaime (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Bennett, J.J. – Benton, Jack and Lois (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Berelson, Bernard – Berry, Iona B. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Berson, Robert C. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bessell, William W. – Billman, Carl (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bing, Jo Watts – Bird, W. H. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bishop, A. – Black, Robert S. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Black, Robert S. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Black, Robert S. – Blair, Tully D. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Blakely, Hunter B. – Blyley, K. G. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Bodine, J. W. – Booher, Edward E. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Boone, Buford – Boozer, Howard R. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Boozer, Howard R. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Boozer, Howard R. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Boren, Orton A. – Branner, A. Lynne (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Branscomb, Harvie (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Branscomb, Louise – Brosnan, John F. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Broughton, J. M. – Brown, Francis (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Brown, Marshall W. – Bryant, Victor S. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Buck, Charles G. – Burton, Herbert (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Bush, R. N. – Byrnes, Arthur F. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Cadbury, William E. – Calkins, W. F. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Callahan, North – Campbell, Russell (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Canfield, Cass – Carman, Margaret (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Carmichael, A. H. – Carmichael, Fred H. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Carmichael, John L. (Mrs.) – Carmichael, Katherine K. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Carmichael, Leonard – Carmichael, Omer (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Carmichael, Patrick H. – Carmichael, William D. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Carney, Thomas P. – Case, Everett (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Caskie, Maxwell – Cecil, George H. V. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Chadwell, Ernest – Chapman, Theodore (Mrs.) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Chappell, Frank – Cheraskin, E. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Childers, James S. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Childs, Thomas W. – Clark, Howard G. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Clark, John B. – Clarke, James M. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Frances – Clydesdale, C.R. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Cochran, William P. – Codd, Leo A. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Cogswell, Sumter – Coleman, Jefferson (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Coleman, John R. – Collier, C.B. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Colligan, Francis J. – Coltrane, D.S. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Colvard, D.W. – Cone, Bonnie (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Conley, Sarah C. – Coombs, Philip H. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Cooper, C.W. – Coppers, A. H. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Cordasce, Francesce – Cousins, Paul M. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Coutts, H. T. – Crel, L.E. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Crelly, H.C. – Cross, G. L. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Crossland, Fred E. – Cunningham, T.R. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Currie, G.A. – da Ponte, Durant (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Darden, Colgate W. – David, O. D. (Mrs.) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - David, O. D. (Mrs.) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Davidson, Jean – Davis, C.G. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Davis, C.G. – Davis, Watson (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Davison, Wilburt C. – Dean, Harris W. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Decker, Catherine K. – Denny, George H. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Derryberry, Everett – Distler, Theodore A. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Dixon, Brewer – Donald, D.C. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Donovan, H.L. – Doyle, Alice N. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Drake, Richard M. – Dugstad, Richard A. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Dugundji, James – Dyer, George C. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Easterling, Louise G. – Edmondson, James H. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Edwards, Fannie – Eiseley, Loren (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. – Elder, J. P. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Eller, E. M. – Martin, George W. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Enerson, Harold L. – Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Eurich, Alvin C (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Eurich, Alvin C. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Evans, B. – Fawcett, Novice G. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Fayer, George S. – Ferguson, Alan D. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Ferguson, Hill – Fine, Benjamin (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Fisher, John L. – Fleming, Sam M. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Flexner, Abraham – Folger, John K. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Folger, Sara – Forrester, Ray (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Foster, Charles H. – Freeman, Thomas J. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - French, Arden O. – Friday, William (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Fridley, Russell W. – Fulbright, J.W. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Fuller, Nelson O. – Gallalee, John M. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Gallan, Gordon T. – Gannon, Robert I. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Gant, George F. – Gardner, John W. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Gardner, John W. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Garner, Paul – Geier, Woodrow A. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Geiger, Albert J. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Geiger, Albert J. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Gentry, Fenton A. – Gideonse, Harry D. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Giesecke, G.E. – Gilmore, E. A. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Glasgow, B.B. – Godfrey, Garland (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Godwin, Winfred L. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Godwin, Winfred L. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Godwin, Winfred L. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Going, Allen – Grant, Jane (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Graves, Bibb – Greenwood, Gordon H. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Gresham, O.C. – Grove, Frank L. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Groves, Leslie R. – Gwyn, Allen H. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Hadley, Morris – Hall, G. Edward (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Harvey P. – Hancher, Virgil M. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Hancher, Virgil M. – Hann, R.D. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Hanna, A. J. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Hanson, Clarence B. – Harmon, Nolan B. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Harnwell, Gaylord P. – Harris, Stella S. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Harrison, DeSales – Harton, John (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Hartz, Fern M. – Havens, R.M. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Haverlin, Carl – Heilbron, Bertha L. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Heimberger, Frederic – Healey, Walter E. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Henry, David D. – Herring, W.D. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Herter, Christian A. – Highsmith, William E. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hildreth, Horace – Hill, Henry H. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Hill, John L. – Hines, Neal O. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Hobson, Jesse E. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Hobson, Margaret W. – Hodson, Earl M. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Hoffman, Jean – Holmes, John (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Holt, A.D. – Hoty, Mrs. Henry G. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - House, J. Albert – Howell, John (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Howell, John (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Howell, Morton B. – Hubbard, L. H. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Hudgins, G. Edward – Hudson, J.G. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Huff, A. Leroy – Hurlbert, Raymond (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Hurley, Helen C. – Hyde, James M. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Hynes, J.W. – Ives, C.A. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ivey, John E., Jr. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Ivey, John E., Jr. (Box 16, Folder 11)